Your first steps in building a day and night image classifier or to
在构建一个白天和夜间图像分类器时 你首先对输入图像
visualize the input images and standardize them to be the same size.
进行了可视化 然后将其归一化为相同大小
To do that, we imported our usual resources and loaded the image datasets.
具体做法是 我们导入了常规资源并加载了图像数据集
And we created a standardized list of all the images and their labels.
然后我们创建了一个所有图像机器标签的归一化列表
Finally, we could visualize the standardized data.
最后 我们就能够可视化这些归一化之后的数据了
Here, I'm selecting the first image in our standardized list and its label.
在这里 我选择归一化列表里的第一幅图像机器标签
I then display the selected image and some information about it.
然后 显示所选图像和部分相关信息
You can see its dimensions and its label, one for day.
你可以看到它的大小和标签 1 代表白天
And finally, we're ready to get all of these images and start
最后 我们就可以把所有这些图像
separating them into two classes, day and night.
分成两个类 白天和夜间了
We'll separate day and night images based on the level of average brightness.
我们基于平均亮度水平来区分白天和夜间图像
This will be a single value and notice that
这会是一个单一值 请注意
day images have a higher average brightness than night images.
白天的图像比夜间图像的平均亮度更高
Now, to calculate the average brightness of an image,
要计算图像的平均亮度
we'll be using HSV colorspace.
我们要使用 HSV 颜色空间
Specifically, we'll use the value channel,
具体来说 我们会使用明度 (value) 通道
which is a measure of brightness,
它用来测量亮度
and add up the pixel values in the value channel.
然后对该通道的像素值求和
Then, we'll divide that sum by the area of
接下来 把总和除以图像面积
the image to get the average value of the image.
得到图像的平均亮度
So, first, I'll convert a test image to HSV colorspace.
首先 我把测试图像转换为 HSV 颜色空间
I want to look at a couple of day images and a couple of
我想看几张白天的图像和几张
night images to find the differences between the two.
夜间的图像 找出两者的区别
In this example, I'm plotting the 'H,' 'S,' and 'V' channels individually.
在本例中 我单独绘制 H、S 和 V 通道
So here's a day image and the colored channels 'H,' 'S,' and 'V'.
这是一张白天的图像 以及不同颜色通道 H、S、V
We can see the 'V' channel is especially high in the sky,
我们可以看到 V 通道的天空亮度特别高
and this classification is based on assuming that a day sky is brighter than a night sky.
这个分类基于的假设是 白天的天空比夜晚的天空亮度高
So our next step will be to find the average brightness using the value channel.
因此 我们的下一步是 利用 V 通道确定平均亮度
Now, I'm going to define a function for finding the average value of an image.
现在 我要定义一个函数 来找到图像的平均值
This function, "average brightness," will take in an rgb_image.
这个函数 avg_brightness 会读入一个 RGB 图像
And the first step will be to convert it to HSV colorspace.
第一步是把图像转换为 HSV 颜色空间
Next, I want to add up all of the pixel values in the value channel,
然后 对 V 通道的所有像素值求和
and I'll do that using numpy sum function.
我使用 numpy 的 sum 函数来实现
This will accept the 'V' channel of our HSV image and adds up all of the pixel values.
它会接受 HSV 图像的 V 通道 并对所有像素值求和
Then I'll calculate the area of my image,
然后 计算图像面积
which I know is 600 by 1100,
这里是 600 乘以 1100
since we standardized each image.
因为我们所有图像都归一化处理过
And to find the average brightness of the image,
要计算图像的平均亮度
we divide this brightness sum by the area of our image.
我们把这个亮度总和除以图像面积
Then this function will return the average.
然后 这个函数会返回平均值
So this gives us one value,
我们得到了一个值
the average brightness or the average value of the image.
图像的平均亮度或平均值
Our next step will be to look at
下一步 我们要看看
day and night images and their average brightness values.
白天和夜间图像 以及它们的亮度值
The goal will be to look at their average brightness and see if we can
我们的目标是 看看它们的平均亮度 确定能否
find a value that clearly separates day and night images.
找到一个值 可以清晰区分白天和夜间图像
So let's first look at our standardized image number zero,
我们先看看归一化后的 0 号图像
which we know is day image.
我们知道 它是一幅白天图像
We see that its average brightness is around 175.
我们看到 它的平均亮度大约是 175
Now, let's look at a night image.
现在 我们看一幅夜间图像
This is a pretty dark image and the average brightness value is just about 35.
这个图像非常暗 平均亮度值约为 35
And we want to look at a variety of these images.
我们要多看一些图像
Here's another day image and its average brightness is around 143.
这是另一张白天图像 平均亮度约为 143
Now, with just a couple of these values in mind,
现在 我们知道了几个值
you might be thinking about how you can use
你可能在想 怎么才能用平均亮度
the average brightness to predict a label for each image,
来为每个图像预测一个标签呢
zero for night or one for day.
0 代表夜间 1 代表白天
And it will be up to you to find that threshold.
因此 你需要找到阈值
The next step will be to feed this data into a classifier.
下一步就是把这个数据馈送到分类器
And the classifier might be as simple as a conditional statement that
分类器可能只是一个简单的条件语句
checks if the average brightness is above some threshold that you define.
检查亮度是否高于你定义的某个阈值
Now, this average brightness value is considered a feature.
这里 平均亮度值被看作一个特征
And a feature is just a measurable component of an image
特征是图像的可测量分量
that ideally helps distinguish it from other images.
能够把一张图像和其他图像区分开来
And we'll soon learn more about testing the accuracy of a model like this.
我们稍后就会学习如何测试这种模型的准确度
Next, we'll learn a bit more about features
接下来 我们在再解一下特征
and why they are useful for self-driving cars.
以及特征为什么对无人驾驶车非常有用